A Guide to the Bailey-Law Collection, 1825-1971
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
- SERIES V. IMAGES, 1904-1942
  - Subseries B. Photographs, 1902-1937
    - Individual eggs and nests
      - Species A-Bk (Box 26, Folder 7)
        Arkansas goldfinch 1904
        Bald eagle 1927
        Bank swallow n.d.
        Barn swallow n.d.
      - Species Bl-Bz (Box 26, Folder 8)
        Black and white warbler (with cowbird) n.d.
        Black-billed cuckoo n.d.
        Black-headed grosbeak n.d. [2 copies]
        Black-necked stilt n.d.
        Blue-winged warbler n.d.
        Bob white n.d. [2 items]
      - Species Ca-Cg (Box 26, Folder 9)
        California towhee 1904
        Canadian grouse n.d.
        Canadian warbler n.d.
        Cape sable seaside sparrow 1921, n.d.
      - Species Ch-E (Box 26, Folder 10)
        Chestnut-sided warbler 1902, n.d. [3 items]
        Chickadee n.d.
        Chipping sparrow n.d.
        Clapper rail n.d.
        Downy woodpecker n.d.
        Duck hawk n.d.
        Dusky seaside sparrow 1920
      - Species F (Box 26, Folder 11)
        Field sparrow n.d.
        Flamingo n.d. [6 items]
        Florida bald eagle 1921
        Florida bob white n.d.
        Florida meadowlark 1922 [2 items]
        Florida nighthawk n.d.
        Florida red-shouldered hawk 1928
        Florida redwing 1920
      - Species G-K (Box 26, Folder 12)
        Grasshopper sparrow n.d.
        Great white heron 1924
        Ground dove n.d. [2 items]
        Hermit thrush n.d.
        Hooded warbler n.d.
        House wren n.d.
        Kingbird 1902
        Kingfisher n.d.
      - Species L-M (Box 26, Folder 13)
        Laughing gull 1910
        Lazuli bunting n.d.
        Least flycatcher (with cowbird) n.d.
        Least tern n.d. [2 items]
        Loggerhead shrike n.d.
        Magnolia warbler n.d.
        Myrtle warbler n.d.
      - Species N-P (Box 26, Folder 14)
        Nashville warbler n.d.
        Northern yellowthroat n.d.
        Olive-sided flycatcher n.d.
        Ovenbird n.d.
        Phoebe 1902 [2 items]
        Prairie warbler n.d.
      - Species Q-R (Box 26, Folder 15)
        Red-billed tropic bird n.d.
        Red-cockaded woodpecker 1918
        Red-winged blackbird n.d.
        Redstart n.d.
        Robin n.d.
        Rose-breasted grosbeak n.d.
        Ruby-throat n.d.
        Ruddy [2 items]
        Russet-backed thrush 1904
      - Species S (Box 26, Folder 16)
        Sage grouse n.d.
        Salt marsh yellow throat n.d. [2 items]
        Samuel's song sparrow n.d. [2 items]
        Sand swallow n.d.
        Scarlet tanager n.d.
        Screech owl n.d.
      - Species T-Wh (Box 26, Folder 17)
        Tennessee warbler n.d.
        Towhee n.d.
        Vermillion flycatcher 1935
        Vesper sparrow n.d.
        Western flycatcher n.d.
        Western mockingbird 1920
        Western red-tailed hawk 1904 [2 copies]
        White-crowned pigeon 1921, n.d.
        White-throated sparrow n.d.
      - Species Wi-Z (Box 26, Folder 18)
        Wilson's plover 1932 n.d. [3 items]
        Wilson's thrush n.d.
        Wilson's warbler n.d.
        Wood ibis n.d. [2 items]
        Wood thrush n.d.
        Worm-eating warbler n.d.
        Yellow-billed cuckoo n.d.
        Yellow warbler n.d.
      - Unidentified species, 1941, n.d., [9 items] (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Birds
      - Species A-B (Box 27, Folder 1)
        Bald eagle n.d. [2 copies]
        Baltimore oriole n.d.
        Black albatross 1913 [2 items]
        Blackbird n.d.
        Blue-footed booby n.d.
        Blue-winged warbler n.d. [2 items]
        Bluebird n.d. [2 items]
        Bridled tern 1921
        Brown pelican n.d.
        Brown thrasher n.d. [2 items]
      - Species C (Box 27, Folder 2)
        Canada goose 1917, n.d. [3 items]
        Canvasback duck 1917
        Catbird n.d. [2 items]
        Chestnut-sided warbler n.d.
        Chickadee n.d. [2 items]
        Chimney swift n.d.
        Crow n.d.
      - Species D-Fli (Box 27, Folder 3)
        Field sparrow n.d. [3 items]
        Flamingo n.d. [3 items]
        Flicker n.d. [2 items]
      - Species Flj-H (Box 27, Folder 4)
        Florida burrowing owl 1920, n.d. [2 items]
        Florida cormorant n.d.
        Florida jay n.d.
        Foster's tern n.d.
        Gannet n.d. [2 items]
        Great blue heron 1904
        Green heron n.d.
        Harlequin ducks n.d.
        Hooded warbler n.d. [2 items]
      - Species I-P (Box 27, Folder 5)
        Least tern n.d. [3 items]
        Little blue heron n.d.
        Louisiana water thrush n.d.
        Man o'war bird n.d.
        Pelican 1935
        Phoebe n.d. [3 items]
      - Species Q-R (Box 27, Folder 6)
        Red-eyed vireo n.d. [4 items]
        Robin n.d. [3 items]
        Rose-breasted grosbeak n.d. [2 items]
      - Species S-V (Box 27, Folder 7)
        Screech owl n.d. [3 items]
        Shrike n.d.
        Song sparrow n.d.
        [Southeastern American kestrel] n.d. [4 items]
        Spotted sandpiper n.d.
      - Species Wa-Wi (Box 27, Folder 8)
        Water ouzel 1905
        Western yellowthroat n.d.
        Whip-poor-will n.d.
        Whistling swan 1917 [2 items]
        White albatross 1913 [2 items]
        White ibis n.d.
        White pelican n.d.[2 items]
        Wild turkey n.d. [2 items]
      - Species Wj-Z (Box 27, Folder 9)
        Wood ibis n.d. [4 items]
        Wood thrush n.d. [3 items]
        Yellow-breasted chat n.d. [2 items]
        Yellow warbler n.d. [2 items]
      - Unidentified species, 1937, n.d., [11 items] (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - People
      - Cooper Ornithological Club, 1923-1924, [2 items] (Box 27, Folder 11)
      - Bird study hike with Lord and Lady Glenconner and others, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 11)
      - Van Hyning and Hardesty with Florida state museum truck, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 11)
      - Unidentified ornithologists in the field, 1922, n.d., [20 items; 2 folders] (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Exhibits (Box 27, Folder 13)
      - Colorado Museum of Natural History bird exhibits, n.d., [2 items]
      - Moses Tanenbaum aviaries, n.d.
      - National Zoological Park aviary, n.d.
      - New York Zoological Park aviary, n.d.
      - Rocky Mountain marmot, n.d.
      - St. Louis Zoo, n.d., [3 items]
      - Unidentified birds given to Bailey by Charles Townsend, 1942
      - Unidentified bird exhibits, n.d., [2 items]
    - Specimens (Box 27, Folder 14)
      - Albatross egg collection, n.d.
      - Streptopelia risoria skins from Bailey collection, n.d.
      - Wingbone of greater snow goose, healed after being shot, n.d.
      - Wingbone of mallard, 1919, [glass plate negatives; 2 items]
      - Unidentified animal skins, n.d.
      - Unidentified animal skulls, n.d.
    - Scenery
      - American Southwest, [1904?], [10 items] (Box 27, Folder 15)
      - Niagara Falls, [1904?], [6 items] (Box 27, Folder 16)
      - St. Louis Expo [Louisiana Purchase Exposition?], [1904?], [6 items] (Box 27, Folder 16)
      - Lake Tahoe, 1920, [2 items] (Box 27, Folder 17)
      - Oil spill aftermath [Virginia?], 1920, [5 items] (Box 27, Folder 17)
      - Fallen Leaf Lake area, California, 1920, [4 items] (Box 27, Folder 17)
      - Water hyacinth on Taylor's Creek, Florida, 1920 (Box 27, Folder 17)
      - Kissimmee prairie, Florida, 1921 (Box 27, Folder 17)
      - Cape Sable prairie country, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 18)
      - Bahamas trip aboard the steamer Berry Islands, n.d., [6 items] (Box 27, Folder 18)
      - Florida Keys scenes, n.d., [2 items] (Box 27, Folder 18)
      - [Stephen Payne home - Oyster, Virginia?], n.d. (Box 27, Folder 18)
      - The Cascades [Pembroke, Virginia], n.d., [2 items] (Box 27, Folder 19)
      - Castle Rock at Pembroke [Virginia], n.d., [2 items] (Box 27, Folder 19)
      - Mountain Lake [Virginia], n.d., [2 items] (Box 27, Folder 19)
      - Phipps Auditorium, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 19)
      - Underwater passage to Lake Cuthbert, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 19)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - Paintings
    - Deer and landscape, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 1)
      [artist unknown; given to Bailey by Charles Townsend]
    - Native American on horseback - by Carl Moon, 1926 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Black rail - by Earl L. Poole, 1912 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Black skimmer - by Earl L. Poole, 1913 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Brown-headed nuthatch - by Earl L. Poole, 1918 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Cabot's tern - by Earl L. Poole, 1912 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - [California quail?] - by Allan Brooks, 1913 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Chuck-will's-widow - by Earl L. Poole, 1912 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Florida Gallinule - by Earl L. Poole, 1912 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Oyster catcher - by Earl L. Poole, 1913 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Piping plover - by Earl L. Poole, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Red-cockaded woodpecker - by Earl L. Poole, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Sandhill crane - by George m. Sutton, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Summer tanager - by Earl L. Poole, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Swainson's warbler - by Earl L. Poole, 1913 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Willet - by Earl L. Poole, 1912 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Yellow-throated vireo - by Earl L. Poole, 1912 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Wild turkey - by Earl L. Poole, 1913 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Maps
    - Map of Key Largo, Florida, 1923 (Box 32, Folder 2)